export const chapter = "Chapter - 10: Habitats of Animals";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What is the main reason India's urban spaces continue to show colonial influence?",
        optionA: "Political changes",
        optionB: "Social changes",
        optionC: "Economic changes",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "De-urbanisation occurs when a town or city loses its importance due to various reasons. Which of the following is NOT mentioned as a potential reason for de-urbanisation in the text?",
        optionA: "Natural calamities",
        optionB: "Religious importance",
        optionC: "Industrial growth",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which town regained its importance, especially due to trade in diamond and cotton after losing significance when Bombay became a major center of trade?",
        optionA: "Surat",
        optionB: "Masulipatnam",
        optionC: "Murshidabad",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What type of towns served as the presidency towns during the colonial period, functioning as capital towns and centers of trade, administration, and military?",
        optionA: "Industrial Towns",
        optionB: "Military Towns",
        optionC: "Hill Stations",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which hill station is mentioned as one that came up during the colonial period and provided respite to the British during extreme hot climate?",
        optionA: "Shimla",
        optionB: "Pachmarhi",
        optionC: "Haridwar",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who is credited for introducing local self-government in municipalities during the colonial period?",
        optionA: "Lord Ripon",
        optionB: "Lord Curzon",
        optionC: "Lord Dalhousie",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary source of income for municipalities in towns, as mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "Government grants",
        optionB: "Local taxes",
        optionC: "Business revenues",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What department was created to construct and maintain various facilities such as roads, hospitals, and libraries during the colonial period?",
        optionA: "Police Department",
        optionB: "Public Works Department (PWD)",
        optionC: "Railway Department",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "When was the first railway line laid down in India during the colonial period?",
        optionA: "1853",
        optionB: "1861",
        optionC: "1902",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What major shortcomings did the British government seek to address when restructuring the police organization in 1902?",
        optionA: "Corruption and inefficiency",
        optionB: "Lack of jurisdiction",
        optionC: "Inadequate funding",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "After independence, India's urban spaces continue to show colonial influence even today due to the ________ changes in political, social, economic, and cultural aspects of life.",
        optionA: "rapid",
        optionB: "enduring",
        optionC: "sporadic",
        correctAnswer: "enduring",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The process of urbanization occurs when a town comes into being and prominence due to various causes. For example, Calcutta and Bombay came into prominence when the British chose them as their centers of trade and then as ________ towns.",
        optionA: "presidency",
        optionB: "rural",
        optionC: "industrial",
        correctAnswer: "presidency",
      },
      {
        question:
          "De-urbanization can occur due to reasons like natural calamities, religious importance, tourism, and ________.",
        optionA: "agricultural growth",
        optionB: "political instability",
        optionC: "commercial decline",
        correctAnswer: "commercial decline",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Surat came to prominence when the East India Company established its factory there in 1612. However, after Bombay fell into its possession, Surat lost its importance. Presently, it has once again become a bustling town, especially due to trade in ________ and cotton.",
        optionA: "silk",
        optionB: "spices",
        optionC: "diamond",
        correctAnswer: "diamond",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Masulipatnam was set up with a factory in 1611 during the British period, but when this factory was shifted to Madras, this town lost its importance, primarily due to changes in ________.",
        optionA: "governance",
        optionB: "economic activities",
        optionC: "climate",
        correctAnswer: "economic activities",
      },
      {
        question:
          "During the colonial period, some Indian entrepreneurs started new industries at places which later developed into important industrial towns, such as ________.",
        optionA: "Jaipur",
        optionB: "Jamshedpur",
        optionC: "Jodhpur",
        correctAnswer: "Jamshedpur",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Hill Stations were established during the colonial period as the British sought cool places to give them respite from the extreme hot climate of India, and places like Darjeeling, Shimla, and Mussoorie were created as summer ________.",
        optionA: "retreats",
        optionB: "resorts",
        optionC: "sanctuaries",
        correctAnswer: "resorts",
      },
      {
        question:
          "A large number of pilgrimage towns have been in existence since earliest times, but with the introduction of railways, many of them became accessible, such as Haridwar, Ayodhya, Varanasi, Ujjain, and ________.",
        optionA: "Mathura",
        optionB: "Hampi",
        optionC: "Mahabalipuram",
        correctAnswer: "Mahabalipuram",
      },
      {
        question:
          "If we look around, we can find that one town often serves more than one purpose; for example, Bhopal serves as the capital town, trade town, tourist town, industrial townâ€”all at the same time. There are numerous other such ________.",
        optionA: "metropolises",
        optionB: "multipurpose towns",
        optionC: "business centers",
        correctAnswer: "multipurpose towns",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British found the native system of town administration very haphazard, so they decided to reform the civic administration by introducing local self-government in municipalities. Lord Ripon favored this change, and he introduced a system where the government would have ultimate control and supervision of all municipalities while the actual administration would rest with the elected representatives of the people. This marked the introduction of local self-government in ________.",
        optionA: "villages",
        optionB: "towns",
        optionC: "colonies",
        correctAnswer: "towns",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "After independence, India's urban spaces no longer show colonial influence.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Urbanization occurs when a town comes into being and prominence due to various causes.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "De-urbanization only occurs due to political reasons.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Surat regained its importance primarily due to the trade in silk.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Hill Stations were established during the colonial period as a response to extreme cold climates in India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Local self-government in municipalities was introduced by Lord Ripon.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Municipalities in towns are primarily funded by the central government.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Public Works Department (PWD) is responsible for the operation of various facilities like schools and parks.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "The first railway line was laid down in India in 1902.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The police organization in colonial India was known for its popularity and integrity among the common people.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
